BASIL HAVENS

ANDROID DEVELOPER

- basilhavens@yahoo.com
- basilhavens.com
- **** 206-880-1713
- **♀** Bellevue. WA
- in basilhavens
- neiligbasil

Not quite 2 years of experience building Android applications. Extensive Java and Kotlin used in Android Studio. See Google Play link for published app and portfolio site for featured apps. Good communication within diverse teams and also works well independently. Eager to continue delivering value with excellence!

Skills

Android, Android Studio, Animations, Coroutines, Custom Views, Debugging, Design Patterns, Espresso, Firebase, Fragments, GitHub, Gradle, Java, JSON, JUnit, JVM, Kotlin, Live Data, MVC, MVVM, Picasso, Room, SQLite, Notifications, OAuth2, REST APIs, Recycler Views, Retrofit, UI, Unit Testing, Writing Tests

Volunteering

Lambda School ·
Meetup Coordinator ·
04/2019 - Present
Seattle, WA

- Attract speakers to monthly meetups for students and alumni
- Coordinate activities through polls, feedback, and seasonal suitability

Apps

Treasure Hunt 04/2020

Android app for CS concepts like blockchain, BFS, and 8-bit CPU programming Android Studio | Kotlin | Retrofit | Fragments | Coroutines | Room | Picasso

- Hidden computer science concepts like blockchain and breadth-first search
- Drew map using a custom view directly on the canvas
- Listened asynchronously for the completion of work using callbacks

Community Calendar

12/2019 - 02/2020

App to empower local organizers to push events to their communities [Play Store] Android Studio | Kotlin | MVVM | Room | OkHttp | Picasso | Espresso | Auth0

- Executed in 2 months with a cross-functional team: 3 Android & 6 Web/UX/iOS
- Planned extensively with mockups, Trello user stories, research, & UX guidance
- Pair-programmed, built up the UI and dialog fragment along with action intents

Health Chaser 05/2019

App for daily activity logging in 8 categories like sleep time and workout regimens Android Studio | Java | Firebase | Live Data | OpenWeatherMap API | Drawer Layout

- Contributed solely to this original idea which can also support multiple users
- Refresh weather data to log activity notes regardless of location
- Integrated Google login, animated GIFs, cloud persistence, and sound effects

Simpsons Says 04/2019

App to show a character quote from the animated TV show *The Simpsons* Android Studio | Java | JSON | OAuth2 | Fragments | RecyclerViews

- Solely responsible for the frontend for the team working on the backend
- Implemented login screen to the backend using OAUTH2 authentication
- Featuring search capability and quote generation via Machine Learning

Employment

Lambda School - Team Lead, Android

Remote - 07/2019 - 11/2019

- Led a team of ~5 Android students in a work setting using Agile methodology
- Reviewed student code via GitHub and provided feedback and suggestions
- Facilitated daily standup meetings to build camaraderie, share ideas, and progress
- Mentored ~3 students on effective learning and solving programming problems
- Graded the students' weekly tests demonstrating sprint topic mastery
- Delivered one-on-one feedback and code reviews on a daily basis

NanoString Technologies - IT Technician

Seattle, WA - 01/2019 - 03/2019

Chess4l ife - Chess Instructor

Bellevue, WA - 05/2017 - 12/2018

Education

Lambda School

03/2019 - 04/2020

Android Development 2020

9-month computer science & software engineering academy that provides an immersive hands-on curriculum with a track focused on Android development

University of Washington BA Germanics & EU Studies 2014 06/2012 - 06/2014